<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title-group>
        <journal-title>Knowledge-Based Systems</journal-title>
      </journal-title-group>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2016.05.035</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Figurative messages and affect in Twitter: Differences between #irony, #sarcasm and #not</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Emilio Sulis</string-name>
          <email>sulis@di.unito.it</email>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Delia Irazú Hernández Farías</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff0">0</xref>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Paolo Rosso</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff0">0</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Viviana Patti</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Giancarlo Ruffo</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref>
        </contrib>
        <aff id="aff0">
          <label>0</label>
          <institution>Universitat Polite?cnica de Vale?ncia</institution>
          ,
          <country country="ES">Spain</country>
        </aff>
        <aff id="aff1">
          <label>1</label>
          <institution>University of Turin</institution>
          ,
          <country country="IT">Italy</country>
        </aff>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
        <year>2016</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>108</volume>
      <issue>2016</issue>
      <fpage>2</fpage>
      <lpage>4</lpage>
      <history>
        <date date-type="accepted">
          <day>17</day>
          <month>5</month>
          <year>2016</year>
        </date>
        <date date-type="received">
          <day>16</day>
          <month>11</month>
          <year>2015</year>
        </date>
        <date date-type="revised">
          <day>16</day>
          <month>5</month>
          <year>2016</year>
        </date>
      </history>
      <abstract>
        <p>a b s t r a c t The use of irony and sarcasm has been proven to be a pervasive phenomenon in social media posing a challenge to sentiment analysis systems. Such devices, in fact, can influence and twist the polarity of an utterance in different ways. A new dataset of over 10,000 tweets including a high variety of figurative language types, manually annotated with sentiment scores, has been released in the context of the task 11 of SemEval-2015. In this paper, we propose an analysis of the tweets in the dataset to investigate the open research issue of how separated figurative linguistic phenomena irony and sarcasm are, with a special focus on the role of features related to the multi-faceted affective information expressed in such texts. We considered for our analysis tweets tagged with #irony and #sarcasm, and also the tag #not, which has not been studied in depth before. A distribution and correlation analysis over a set of features, including a wide variety of psycholinguistic and emotional features, suggests arguments for the separation between irony and sarcasm. The outcome is a novel set of sentiment, structural and psycholinguistic features evaluated in binary classification experiments. We report about classification experiments carried out on a previously used corpus for #irony vs #sarcasm. We outperform in terms of F-measure the stateof-the-art results on this dataset. Overall, our results confirm the difficulty of the task, but introduce new data-driven arguments for the separation between #irony and #sarcasm. Interestingly, #not emerges as a distinct phenomenon.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group>
        <kwd>Figurative language</kwd>
        <kwd>Affective knowledge</kwd>
        <kwd>Irony</kwd>
        <kwd>Sarcasm</kwd>
        <kwd>Twitter</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <sec id="sec-1">
      <title>-</title>
      <p>i n f o</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-2">
      <title>1. Introduction</title>
      <p>The use of figurative devices such as irony and sarcasm has
been proven to be a pervasive phenomenon on social media
platforms such as Twitter and poses a significant challenge to
sentiment analysis systems, since irony-laden expressions can play the
role of polarity reversers [1]. Irony and sarcasm can influence and
twist the affect of an utterance in complex and different ways.
They can elicit various affective reactions, and can behave
differently with respect to the polarity reversal phenomenon, as shown
in [2]. However, the issue of distinguishing between such devices
is still poorly understood. In particular, the question of whether
irony and sarcasm are separated or similar linguistic phenomena
is a controversial issue in literature and no clear consensus has
already been reached. Although some researchers consider them
strongly related figurative devices, other authors proposed a
separation: sarcasm is offensive, more aggressive than irony [3,4] and
delivered with a cutting tone (rarely ambiguous), whereas irony
often exhibits great subtlety and has been considered more similar
to mocking in a sharp and non-offensive manner [5]. Furthermore,
there is a consistent body of work on computational models for
sarcasm detection [6] and irony detection [7] in social media, but
only preliminary studies addressed the task to distinguish sarcasm
and irony [8,9].</p>
      <p>In this paper we contribute to the debate of whether irony
and sarcasm are similar or distinct phenomena by investigating
how hashtags marking a figurative intent are used in Twitter. Our
experiments concern a rich corpus of figurative messages. We
considered tweets marked with the user-generated tags #irony
and #sarcasm, as such tags reflect a tacit belief about what
constitutes irony and sarcasm, respectively [7]. We extend our
analysis also to tweets tagged with hashtag #not, previously used
to retrieve sarcastic tweets [6,10], in order to investigate further
their figurative meaning. Samples of tweets marked with different
hashtags follow:
(tw1) Fun fact of the day: No one knows who invented the fire
hydrant because its patent was destroyed in a fire. #irony
(tw2) I just love it when I speak to folk and they totally ignore
me!!! #Sarcasm!
(tw3) So I just colored with Ava for an hour. Yeah my summer so
far has been so fun [smiling face emoji] #not</p>
      <p>Our methodology comprehends two steps. First, we performed
a distribution and correlation analysis relying on the dataset of
SemEval2015-Task11 [1], which includes samples of the kinds of
figurative messages under consideration here (step 1). We explored
the use of the three hashtags including structural as well as
psycholinguistic and affective features concerning emotional
information.</p>
      <p>The affective information expressed in the dataset is
multifaceted. Both sentiment and emotion lexicons, as well as
psycholinguistic resources available for English, refer to various affective
models and capture different facets of affect, such as sentiment
polarity, emotional categories and emotional dimensions. Some of such
resources, i.e., SenticNet [11] and EmoSenticNet [12], are not flat
vocabularies of affective words, but include and model semantic,
conceptual and affective information associated with multi-word
natural language expressions, by enabling concept-level analysis of
sentiment and emotions conveyed in texts. In our view, all such
resources represent a rich and varied lexical knowledge about affect,
under different perspectives, therefore we propose here a
comprehensive study of their use in the context of our analysis, in order
to test if they convey relevant knowledge to distinguishing
different kinds of figurative messages.</p>
      <p>The analysis provided valuable insights on three kinds of
figurative messages, including different ways to influence and twist the
affective content. The outcome is a novel set of features evaluated
in binary classification experiments (step 2). To better understand
the impact of each feature, we evaluated our model performing
experiments with different subset combinations, proceeding also by
feature ablation, i.e. removing one feature at time in order to
evaluate its contribution on the results.</p>
      <p>To sum up, our experiments address the following research
questions:
1. Is it possible to distinguish irony from sarcasm?
2. What is the role of the #not hashtag as a figurative language
device? Is it a synonym of irony, of sarcasm, or something in
between?
3. Does information about sentiment and psycholinguistics
features help in distinguishing among #irony, #sarcasm and
#not tweets?
4. What is the role of the polarity reversal in the three kinds
of figurative messages?</p>
      <p>Overall, results confirm the difficulty of the task, but introduce
new data-driven arguments for the separation between #irony and
#sarcasm. As shown in the next sections, we outperform the
stateof-the-art results in #irony vs #sarcasm classification from 0.62
[9] to 0.70, in terms of F-measure.</p>
      <p>As for the separation of #irony vs #not and #sarcasm vs #not,
interestingly, #not emerges as a distinct phenomenon. Analysis of
the relevance of each feature in the model confirms the
significance of sentiment and psycholinguistics features. Finally, an
interesting finding about polarity reversal is given by correlation
study presented in Section 4.2.3: the polarity reversal phenomenon
seems to be relevant in messages marked with #sarcasm and #not,
while it is less relevant for messages tagged with #irony.</p>
      <p>The paper is structured as follows. Section 2 surveys main
issues in literature about irony and the like. In Section 3 we
describe the corpus and the resources exploited in our approach.
Section 4 presents the feature analysis and Section 5 describes our
experiments. Section 6 concludes the paper.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-3">
      <title>2. Irony, sarcasm et similia</title>
      <p>Many authors embrace an overall view on irony. Broadly
speaking, under the umbrella term of irony one can find distinct
phenomena such as situational irony or verbal irony [13?15]. Situational
irony (or ?irony of fate?) refers to the state of affairs or events
which is the reverse of what has been expected, while the term
verbal irony is applied to refer to a figure of speech,
characterized by the possibility of distinguishing between a literal and an
intended/implied meaning. In particular, according to many
theoretical accounts in ironic utterances the speaker intends to
communicate the opposite of what is literally said [16,17], but since
such definition does not allow to account for many samples of
utterances which are considered ironic, we prefer to refer to a more
general position, on which different authors in literature would
tacitly agree: ?Regardless of the type, or absence, of meaning
negation/reversal, the literal import of an ironic utterance differs from
the implicit meaning the speaker intends to communicate? [15].
Moreover, we can have an ironic statement, meant as utterance of
a speaker which refers to certain aspects of an ironic situation [13].</p>
      <p>In linguistics, verbal irony is sometimes used as a synonym of
sarcasm [18?20]. According to the literature, boundaries in
meaning between irony, sarcasm et similia are fuzzy. While some
authors consider irony as an umbrella term covering also sarcasm
[16,21,22], others provide insights for a separation. Sarcasm has
been recognized in [23] with a specific target to attack [4,15], more
offensive [3] and ?intimately associated with particular negative
affective states? [24]. According to [3] hearers perceive
aggressiveness as the feature that distinguishes sarcasm. Instead, irony has
been considered more similar to mocking in a sharp and
nonoffensive manner [5].</p>
      <p>The presence of irony-related figurative devices is becoming one
of the most interesting aspects to check in social media corpora
since it can play the role of polarity reverser with respect to the
words used in the text unit [25]. However, a variety of typologies
of figurative messages can be recognized in tweets: from irony to
sarcastic posts, and to facetious tweets that can be playful, aimed
at amusing or at strengthening ties with other users. Ironic and
sarcastic devices can express different interpersonal meaning, elicit
different affective reactions, and can behave differently with
respect to the polarity reversal phenomenon [2]. Therefore, to
distinguish between them can be important for improving the
performances of systems in sentiment analysis.</p>
      <p>For computational linguistics purposes irony and sarcasm are
often viewed as the same figurative language device.
Computational models for sarcasm detection [6,9,26?28] and irony
detection [7,29,30] in social media has been proposed, mostly focussed
on Twitter. Only a few preliminary studies addressed the task to
investigate the differences between irony and sarcasm [8,9]. The
current work aims to further contribute to this subject.</p>
      <p>Furthermore, a rarely investigated form of irony that can be
interesting to study in social media is self-mockery. Self-mockery
seems to be different from other forms of irony, also from sarcasm,
because it does not involve contempt for others, but the speaker
wishes to dissociate from the content of the utterance.
According to some theoretical accounts: ?Self-mockery usually involves
a speaker making an utterance and then immediately denying or
invalidating its consequence, often by saying something like ?No, I
was just kidding?? [31]. Moreover, the analysis of complex forms of
self-mockery in spontaneous conversations in [32] highlighted
in</p>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
    <ref-list />
  </back>
</article>

