<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title-group>
        <journal-title>Mining Twitter for Fine-Grained Political Opin-
ion Polarity Classification, Ideology Detection and Sarcasm Detection. In
WSDM</journal-title>
      </journal-title-group>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Mining Twiter for Fine-Grained Political Opinion Polarity Classification, Ideology Detection and Sarcasm Detection</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <string-name>Sandeepa Kannangara</string-name>
          <email>s.kannangara@unsw.edu.au</email>
          <xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff0">0</xref>
        </contrib>
        <aff id="aff0">
          <label>0</label>
          <institution>School of Computer Science and Engineering University of New South Wales Sydney NSW 2052</institution>
          ,
          <country country="AU">Australia</country>
        </aff>
      </contrib-group>
      <pub-date>
        <year>2018</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <fpage>751</fpage>
      <lpage>752</lpage>
      <abstract>
        <p>In this paper, we propose three models for socio-political opinion polarity classification of microblog posts. Firstly, a novel probabilistic model, Joint-Entity-Sentiment-Topic (JEST) model, which captures opinions as a combination of the target entity, sentiment and topic, will be proposed. Secondly, a model for ideology detection called JEST-Ideology will be proposed to identify an individual's orientation towards topics/issues and target entities by extending the proposed opinion polarity classification framework. Finally, we propose a novel method to accurately detect sarcastic opinions by utilizing detected fine-grained opinion and ideology.</p>
      </abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <sec id="sec-1">
      <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
      <p>Opinions in social media platforms provide worldwide access to
what people think about daily life topics/issues. Thus exploiting
such a source of information to understand public opinion can
be very useful in many scenarios, for example by political parties
interested in monitoring attitudes towards their policies.</p>
      <p>
        The opinion mining research field aims to develop automated
approaches to accurately analyse such opinion data. Although there
is much previous work on opinion mining, the majority of early
studies analysed text documents such as product and movie reviews
[
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
        ]. Only a limited number of studies have attempted to analyse
public opinion in a political context [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>
        ]. The nature of political
discourse which often includes sarcasm and irony makes the analysis
more challenging.
      </p>
      <p>
        Most political opinion mining studies analysed election datasets
with the aim of election result prediction. The approaches employed
range from lexicon based methods [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
        ] to supervised machine
learning methods using algorithms such as SVM [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>
        ] and Deep Learning
approaches [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
        ] in recent years. However, most work in this area
focuses on overall sentiment classification, though Maynard and
Funk [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref>
        ] considered identification of the opinion target and
Vijayaraghavan et al. [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">11</xref>
        ] addressed classification of the topics along
with the sentiment.
      </p>
      <p>
        An opinion is defined as a tuple of four components [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref>
        ]:
sentiment orientation, sentiment target, opinion holder, and time. The
sentiment target is defined as an entity or an entity with possibily
an aspect of the entity that the sentiment has been expressed upon.
As an example, if a tweet expresses a negative sentiment towards
the Labor Party regarding Employment/Jobs, Labor Party is the
target entity and Employment/Jobs is the aspect of the entity. However,
the majority of early studies in opinion mining attempted to detect
only the overall sentiment [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref>
        ], regardless of the entities mentioned
and their aspects. After Hu and Liu?s [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">5</xref>
        ] study, fine-grained opinion
mining/aspect-based opinion mining became prominent. However,
most of the aspect-based opinion mining studies [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>
        ] identified only
aspect and sentiment by assuming a known target.
      </p>
      <p>In this research, we aim to address the current challenges in
sociopolitical opinion mining from Twitter focusing on the identification
of target entity, aspect and sentiment for fine-grained opinion
mining. Identifying an individual?s political ideology/orientation from
their reviews is also an important task for analysing political
opinions. In general, opinions expressed toward the issues/topics of
target entities are often indicative of political ideologies. For that,
we propose a novel approach utilising the proposed opinion
mining framework. Further, the presence of sarcasm is identified as
a challenge for opinion polarity classification since sarcasm can
potentially flip the polarity of the review. In this research, we will
propose a novel method to detect sarcasm in tweets.
2</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-2">
      <title>THE PROPOSED RESEARCH</title>
      <p>Overall, the aim of this research is to develop a framework for
political opinion mining focusing on fine-grained opinion mining,
sarcasm detection and ideology detection. To evaluate each
proposed model, we use tweets collected during the 2016 Australasian
Federal Election.
2.1</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-3">
      <title>Fine-Grained Political Opinion Polarity</title>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-4">
      <title>Classification</title>
      <p>
        In this study, for fine-grained political opinion mining, we aim to
extract the opinion target (e.g. candidates and political parties),
topics discussed (e.g. Tax/Negative Gearing, Asylum Seekers/Refugees,
etc.) and sentiment (Positive, Negative or Neutral) towards the
target from each tweet. For this, we propose a fine-grained opinion
mining model, called JEST (Joint-Entity-Sentiment-Topic), to jointly
model all three dimensions, based on LDA [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref>
        ].
      </p>
      <p>The strength of JEST is that all the component dimensions can
help to improve each other during the joint modelling process. The
rationale here is that it is possible to model each dimension as a
latent variable in a graphical model. To distinguish the aspect and
entity in the model, we utilize a knowledge base of entities which
contains common names and hashtags used to represent entities in
a predefined entity list. In this model, we assume that there is only
one target entity and several or no topics in each tweet.</p>
      <p>For evaluation, we use perplexity, which is the standard measure
for evaluating topic models to compare the model with the selected
baseline models. Furthermore, we will evaluate the document
classification performance using distributions of the entity, target and
sentiment generated by the model. However, since there is no prior
work that models these three dimensions with similar assumptions,
we need to select diferent baselines to evaluate each dimension.
Furthermore, we can do qualitative analysis by manually inspecting
the quality of the output.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-5">
      <title>2.2 Political Orientation Detection</title>
      <p>For political orientation detection, we aim to identify a Twitter
user?s political alignment. However, our definition of political
alignment is a user?s set of political preferences over a range of policy
positions of a party. For this, knowing the information such as
user?s opinion towards candidates or parties and topics that are
discussed in his/her tweets is important. We model such evidence
in our JEST model and here we propose an extension of JEST, the
JEST-Ideology model, incorporating the ideology dimension.</p>
      <p>The JEST model is capable of identifying an entity, sentiment
and topics for each tweet in the corpus. The JEST-Ideology model
has a top layer which can identify the favourable topics and entities
for each user. However, there can be tweets that do not contain
topics but generally express an opinion towards an entity. We
consider such situations by modelling the general ideology of the user
towards entities. The generative process runs through each user
and then tweets of each user. For the evaluation of the model, we
can use the same approaches proposed for the JEST model.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-6">
      <title>2.3 Sarcasm Detection in Political Tweets</title>
      <p>
        Most previous approaches to sarcasm detection treat it as a purely
linguistic matter, using information such as lexical cues and their
corresponding sentiment as predictive features [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref>
        ]. However,
sarcasm has been extensively studied in the behavioural sciences and
there are several theories explaining when, how and why sarcasm
is expressed [
        <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>
        ]. Those theories can be represented as contextual
features by consider the user?s current and previous posts.
      </p>
      <p>In this research, we propose to use both linguistic and contextual
features to detect sarcastic tweets. The accepted view is that sarcasm
potentially flip the polarity of a review. Therefore, when we know
the surface polarity of a tweet, to identify the situations where the
actual polarity is diferent from surface polarity we can use the
ideology of the author. If the ideology of the author is diferent
from the surface polarity then we can infer that it is a sarcastic
tweet. Therefore, as contextual features for the supervised model,
we can use the ideology of the Twitter user and surface polarity by
utilizing the results of JEST and JEST-Ideology models.</p>
      <p>The performance of the proposed approach can be measured
using accuracy, recall, precision and F-measure. Further, we will
compare our models with existing sarcasm detection techniques.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-7">
      <title>3 CONCLUSION AND FUTURE WORK</title>
      <p>This paper gives a brief overview of ongoing research on political
opinion mining. We have identified three main research directions
to automatically analyse political opinions in Twitter: fine-grained
opinion polarity classification, ideology detection and sarcasm
detection. We propose novel topic models, JEST and JEST-Ideology,
which are capable of fine-grained opinion mining and ideology
detection respectively. Finally, with the aim of improving opinion
polarity classification performance, we propose a novel sarcasm
detection model which uses ideology and fine-grained opinion as
features with other linguistic features to classify sarcastic opinions.</p>
      <p>In the future, it is essential to build these proposed models and
evaluate model performance. A number of experiments are planned
to select best performing model for each problem. Although, the
models are proposed for the political domain, they are also
applicable for other domain. Therefore, we are planning to conduct
experiments using other datasets from diferent domains to evaluate
the performance of the proposed models.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec-8">
      <title>4 ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title>
      <p>I would like to sincerely thank my supervisor Wayne Wobcke,
and Michael Bain, Alfred Krzywicki and Bradford Heap for their
continuous mentoring and constant support. The work is supported
by the Data to Decisions Cooperative Research Centre.</p>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
    <ref-list>
      <ref id="ref1">
        <mixed-citation>
          [1]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Akshat</given-names>
            <surname>Bakliwal</surname>
          </string-name>
          , Jennifer Foster, Jennifer van der Puil,
          <string-name>
            <surname>Ron O'Brien</surname>
            ,
            <given-names>Lamia</given-names>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Tounsi</surname>
            , and
            <given-names>Mark</given-names>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Hughes</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2013</year>
          .
          <article-title>Sentiment Analysis of Political Tweets: Towards an Accurate Classifier</article-title>
          .
          <source>In Proceedings of the Workshop on Language in Social Media (LASM '13)</source>
          .
          <fpage>49</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>58</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref2">
        <mixed-citation>
          [2]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>David</given-names>
            <surname>Bamman</surname>
          </string-name>
          and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Noah A.</given-names>
            <surname>Smith</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2015</year>
          .
          <article-title>Contextualized Sarcasm Detection on Twitter</article-title>
          .
          <source>In Proceedings of the Ninth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media (ICWSM '15)</source>
          .
          <fpage>574</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>577</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref3">
        <mixed-citation>
          [3]
          <string-name>
            <surname>David</surname>
            <given-names>M.</given-names>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Blei</surname>
            ,
            <given-names>Andrew Y.</given-names>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Ng</surname>
            , and
            <given-names>Michael I.</given-names>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Jordan</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2003</year>
          .
          <article-title>Latent Dirichlet Allocation</article-title>
          .
          <source>Journal of Machine Learning Research</source>
          <volume>3</volume>
          (
          <year>2003</year>
          ),
          <fpage>993</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>1022</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref4">
        <mixed-citation>
          [4]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Hsinchun</given-names>
            <surname>Chen</surname>
          </string-name>
          and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>David</given-names>
            <surname>Zimbra</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2010</year>
          .
          <article-title>AI and Opinion Mining</article-title>
          .
          <source>IEEE Intelligent Systems</source>
          <volume>25</volume>
          ,
          <issue>3</issue>
          (
          <year>2010</year>
          ),
          <fpage>74</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>80</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref5">
        <mixed-citation>
          [5]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Minqing</given-names>
            <surname>Hu</surname>
          </string-name>
          and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Bing</given-names>
            <surname>Liu</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2004</year>
          .
          <article-title>Mining and Summarizing Customer Reviews</article-title>
          .
          <source>In Proceedings of the Tenth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD '04)</source>
          .
          <fpage>168</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>177</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref6">
        <mixed-citation>
          [6]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Farhan</given-names>
            <surname>Hassan</surname>
          </string-name>
          <string-name>
            <surname>Khan</surname>
          </string-name>
          , Saba Bashir, and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Usman</given-names>
            <surname>Qamar</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2014</year>
          . TOM:
          <article-title>Twitter Opinion Mining Framework Using Hybrid Classification Scheme</article-title>
          .
          <source>Decision Support Systems</source>
          <volume>57</volume>
          (
          <year>2014</year>
          ),
          <fpage>245</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>257</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref7">
        <mixed-citation>
          [7]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Bing</given-names>
            <surname>Liu</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2012</year>
          .
          <article-title>Sentiment Analysis and Opinion Mining</article-title>
          . Morgan &amp; Claypool.
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref8">
        <mixed-citation>
          [8]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Diana</given-names>
            <surname>Maynard</surname>
          </string-name>
          and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Adam</given-names>
            <surname>Funk</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2012</year>
          .
          <article-title>Automatic Detection of Political Opinions in Tweets</article-title>
          . In The Semantic Web:
          <article-title>ESWC 2011 Workshops, Raúl García-Castro, Dieter Fensel</article-title>
          , and Grigoris Antoniou (Eds.). Springer-Verlag, Berlin,
          <fpage>88</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>99</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref9">
        <mixed-citation>
          [9]
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Guang</given-names>
            <surname>Qiu</surname>
          </string-name>
          , Bing Liu, Jiajun Bu, and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Chun</given-names>
            <surname>Chen</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2011</year>
          .
          <article-title>Opinion Word Expansion and Target Extraction through Double Propagation</article-title>
          .
          <source>Computational Linguistics</source>
          <volume>37</volume>
          ,
          <issue>1</issue>
          (
          <year>2011</year>
          ),
          <fpage>9</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>27</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref10">
        <mixed-citation>
          [10]
          <string-name>
            <surname>Ashwin</surname>
            <given-names>Rajadesingan</given-names>
          </string-name>
          , Reza Zafarani, and Huan Liu.
          <year>2015</year>
          .
          <article-title>Sarcasm Detection on Twitter: A Behavioral Modeling Approach</article-title>
          .
          <source>In Proceedings of the Eighth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM '15)</source>
          .
          <fpage>97</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>106</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref11">
        <mixed-citation>
          [11]
          <string-name>
            <surname>Prashanth</surname>
            <given-names>Vijayaraghavan</given-names>
          </string-name>
          , Soroush Vosoughi, and
          <string-name>
            <given-names>Deb</given-names>
            <surname>Roy</surname>
          </string-name>
          .
          <year>2016</year>
          .
          <article-title>Automatic Detection and Categorization of Election-Related Tweets</article-title>
          .
          <source>In Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Web and Social Media (ICWSM '16)</source>
          .
          <fpage>703</fpage>
          -
          <lpage>706</lpage>
          .
        </mixed-citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
  </back>
</article>

